Baluraj

Mavelikkara, Kerala, India • +91 9447707213 • sivams20@gmail.com • LinkedIn • GitHub

Frontend Developer

I am a senior front end developer with 10 years of professional experience. Proficient with Requirement Analysis, Unit Testing and Application maintenance. Having good understanding of modern tooling and development techniques. Self-motivated and keen to learn new technologies.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- React JS
- HMTL 5
- SASS, SCSS
- Jasmine
- NPM

- Typescript
- Node JS
- ES6
- Git
- Karma
- InVision

- Angular 2+
- CSS 3
- RxJs
- Webpack
- RESTful API

EXPERIENCE

Senior Front End Engineer, Tech Mahindra

Dec 2021 - Present

- Advisory Fee Calculator (Banking and Finance, USA)
 - o Designed and implemented different features for banking and finance application.
 - o Delivered different features and other enhancements of the app.
 - o Ideated on the UX implementation and improvements for the application.
 - o Improved the performance of the application.
 - o Involved in product and UX review.

Senior Front End Engineer, Infosys Limited

Oct 2018 - Nov 2021

- Connect (Logistics, EU)
 - Designed and implemented different features for logistic application, prototypes, and interfaces including RWD.
 - o Ideated on the UX implementation and improvements for the application.
 - Improved the performance of the application by reducing the build time and followed best practices.
 - o Involved in requirement gathering sessions with different business stakeholders.
 - o Involved in product and UX review.
 - o Involved in architecture design sessions for converting mono repo into micro frontend architecture design.
 - o Reduced build time by converting the mono repo into micro frontend architecture design.
 - o Involved in code review.
 - o Presented the product evolution phases as demo at the end of each Agile Sprint.
 - o Implemented unit testing with Karma and Jasmine.

Front End Engineer, Cognizant Technology Solution

Jan 2015 - Sep 2018

- **BCM** (Business Continuity Management)
 - Contributed main features for a Business Continuity Management (BCM) application, which helps to continue business in threats such as natural disasters or data breaches and protect the business interests of the organization.
 - Created custom components and directives that can be used throughout the application.
 - o Implemented common error handling for the entire application.
 - o Delivered different features and other enhancements of the app.
 - o Ideated on the UX implementation and improvements for the application.
 - o Involved in product and UX review.

Software Engineer, Citrus Informatics Pvt Ltd

Oct 2013 – Jan 2015

- **PrescribeWell** (*Healthcare*, *USA*)
 - Learned AngularJS.
 - Contributed custom components and directives that can be used throughout the application.
 - o Worked on mobile web application for prescribewell.

Junior Software Engineer, Cynere Infotech Pvt Ltd

Feb 2012 - Oct 2013

- Advertisement tracking system
 - o Designed and implemented different features for the application.
 - Involved in all the phases of project from requirement analysis till the deployment of the project.

Languages

English – Professional Proficiency Malayalam - Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Education

 $\begin{array}{l} \text{Master of Computer Application} - \textbf{61.5\%} \\ \text{Mar Athanasious College for Advanced Studies} \\ 10/2008 - 04/2012 \end{array}$